Finding Aid for the Ralph Story Papers LSC.0867
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph Story papers
1940-2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
Story, Ralph
LSC.0867
33.0 Linear Feet (66 document boxes and 9 oversize boxes)
Ralph Story was a broadcast journalist and television host for more than four decades, hosting programs such as Ralph Story's Los Angeles-- an Emmy-winning weekly magazine series that ran on KNXT-TV from 1964 to 1970, The $64,000 challenge, Ralph Story's A.M., the KNXT Channel 2 Evening News and numerous prime time specials. Renowned especially for his local interest reporting, Story served as correspondent, reporter and anchor for radio and television news from the 1940s to the 1980s, and was a prolific lecturer on the media and California history. The collection consists of scripts and professional documentation spanning Story's career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Ralph Story's Los Angeles scripts, donated ca. 1965
Addition, and bulk of the collection, gift of Diana Story, December 2008
Addition, predominantly photographs, clippings, and albums, gift of Diana Story, November 2009
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9932223433606533
Biography/History
Ralph Story (August 19, 1920 - September 26, 2006) was born Ralph Bernard Snyder in Kalamazoo, Michigan. In high school and at Western Michigan College, he worked part time as a radio announcer, and eventually left college to pursue a career in radio full time first in Grand Rapids, Michigan and then Buffalo, New York. His career was interrupted when he joined the Air Force during World War II. Already a licensed pilot, he served first as a flight instructor and then flew 63 missions over Europe as a P-51 fighter pilot. After the war, he returned to Buffalo to work as an announcer and program director for CBS radio affiliate WGR. In 1948, CBS radio transferred him to Los Angeles. There, he served as program director and morning DJ at KNX and changed his name to Ralph Story. While at KNX, the Military Air Transport Service invited Story to visit and interview for broadcast servicemen and civilians from California stationed around the world. The result was California Around the World, broadcast on CBS radio.
After a brief stint as host of the game show What Do You Have in Common?, Story moved to New York City to emcee The $64,000 Challenge from 1956-1958, when it was cancelled in the wake of the quiz show scandal. Story returned to Los Angeles and for the next forty years hosted, wrote and produced for radio and television, exploring and shaping such formats as talk radio, news broadcasting, human interest and local color reporting, and the magazine show. The bulk of his broadcast career was spent at KNX radio and its sister television station KNXT, both CBS affiliates. However, Story also worked for KABC, KNBC, KCET, KCAL, and independent production companies including National General and O'Connor radio.
In addition to his serialized weekly and daily programs and radio spots, Story hosted a variety of special programs, including prime-time specials, award ceremonies, and local events such as the Tournament of Roses Parade and Hollywood Bowl concerts. He was also a prolific producer, writer and lecturer on local and California history, and prepared but did not publish a guidebook to Los Angeles. Story was active in civic and professional groups, hosting celebrity tennis events and serving as grand marshal for numerous local festivals and functions. He was a fundraiser for Public Television stations KCET and KOCE and a frequent speaker at community and educational meetings.
Story is best remembered for his detailed research and his wry and witty observations about life in California and especially in Los Angeles. Television work includes: the "Human Predicament" on KNXT's The Big News, Ralph Story's Los Angeles, Ralph Story's AM, The Channel 2 News, It's a Nice Place..., The Sunday Show, On the Road Again, The Wine Game, Things That Aren't Here Anymore and More Things That Aren't Here Anymore.
Story's radio titles include: The Ralph Story Show, Top of the Morning, Storyline, Hollywood Today, Dimension in Hollywood, Meet the Cook, Food News, You're the Judge and an annual Christmas Morning special.
In 1984, the Academy of Television Arts and Sciences awarded Story their highest honor, the Governors Award. Other awards Story received throughout his career include numerous Los Angeles Area Emmys and Golden Mikes, two Directors Guild of America Awards, and many local and professional honors.
Ralph Story died on September 26, 2006 after a long battle with emphysema at the age of 86 in Los Angeles, California.
Scope and Content
This collection documents the activities of Ralph Story, a broadcast journalist and television host. An original donation of 208 scripts for Ralph Story's Los Angeles was supplemented in 2008 with approximately 40 more scripts from Ralph Story's Los Angeles, and scripts, research and production materials spanning Story's career. The bulk of the collection consists of broadcast scripts, clippings, contracts, correspondence, financial and legal material, production records, photographs, research material, draft chapters of a guidebook, miscellaneous printed matter and ephemera.
Organization and Arrangement
Creator's original order has been retained and arranged into the following series:
1. Broadcasting
1.1 Radio
1.2 Television serial programming
1.3 Television special programming
2. Print projects
3. Personal Appearances-lectures and speeches, cameos, hosting gigs, commercials
4. Professional Career/History
4.1 Correspondence
4.2 Awards
4.3 Contracts
4.4 Biographies and clippings
4.5 Research, uncategorized
5. Photographs
5.1 Ralph Story
5.2 Studio press kits for various films
6. Personal
Related Material
The UCLA Film and Television Archive holds various items spanning Ralph Story's career in television broadcasting, including over 100 episodes of Ralph Story's Los Angeles, selected specials, news programs, and early television work.
Television scripts.; Television personalities -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Los Angeles (Calif.) -- History.; Story, Ralph--Archives.
- 1. Broadcasting -- Radio and Television
  Scope and Contents note
  Scripts, research, some correspondence (where originally filed with program materials), proposals, production records.
  - Radio, 1949 - 1978
    Scripts and research materials for radio programs broadcast on WGR, KNX and CBS national radio network. This series also includes proposals for television programs that evolved from radio series.
    - Early radio scripts -- Lone Ranger sample script, "Frederick's Hand Dexter" (partial script), 1940s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 4 Radio plays for WGR Buffalo, New York and United States Corps of Engineers, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      "The Day the Niagra Flowed Backward," "The Voyage of L-T-5," "The Breakwater," "The Men with Hairy Ears"
    - KNX/CBS radio scripts, 1948, 1951, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      "Stars in the Morning" script for audition recording, "Top of the Morning"
    - "The Ralph Snyder Show" proposal for morning television show, pitch and sample script, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - CBS radio-- "California Around the World," Military Air Transport Service (MATS) world tour -- scripts, records and publicity photos, 1951 - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - CBS radio -- "California Around the World," Military Air Transport Service (MATS) world tour -- research, 1951 - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Includes mementos, maps, menus, postcards, photos acquired from Christian Dior and others, and one candid photo of Ralph Story in front of Acropolis
    - CBS radio -- Dimension ? in Hollywood (aka "Hollywood Today"), 1968 and others (Box 1, Folder 7)
      10 scripts of spots that ran on CBS radio from 1961 - 1971
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- publicity and samples, 1976 -1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- source material, column "Trials and Tribulations" by Florence K. Palmer, 1967 March 1 - 1967 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Columns 187 - 208
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- source material, column "Trials and Tribulations" by Florence K. Palmer, 1967 May 3 - 1967 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Columns 209 - 260
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1976 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      31 scripts (generic promos and numbers 1161 - 1184, 1192)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1976 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      11 scripts (numbers 1101, 1102, 1105, 1106, 1109, 1113, 1117, 1118, 1120 - 1122)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1976 December 13 and December 27 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      25 scripts (numbers 1123, 1128, 1140, 1132, 1110, 1103, 1104, 1126, 1127, 1112, 1108, 1116, 1124, 1119, 1125, 1114, 1130, 1131, 1133, 1134, 1143, 1144, 1148, 1149, 1185)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 January 10 and January 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      40 scripts (numbers 1186 - 1191, 1193 - 1195, 1152, 1153, 1155, 1154, 1156 - 1160, 1129, 1135, 1136 - 1139, 1141, 1145 - 1147, 1150, 1151, 1097 - 110, 1107, 1111, 1142, 0001, 0002, 0003)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 February 15 - 16, and March 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Promos and 40 scripts ( numbers 4 - 44)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      20 scripts (numbers 45 - 65)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      24 scripts (67 - 69, 71 - 92)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 September 23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      12 scripts (numbers 93 - 104)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 October 3 and October 27 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      38 scripts (numbers 105 - 142)
    - "You're the Judge" -- syndicated spots -- scripts, 1977 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      34 scripts (numbers 143- 160, 163 - 177, 181)
    - CBS radio "Meet the Cook" -- memos, publicity, promo script, 1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - CBS radio "Meet the Cook" -- recipes, 1977 April 11 - 1977 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - CBS radio "Meet the Cook" -- recipes, 1977 November 14 - 1978 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - KNX radio "Food News" -- script, 1977 November 22 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- press releases, correspondence and newspaper clippings on various topics, 1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- press releases, correspondence and newspaper clippings on various topics, 1977 - 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- potential guests -- press releases, correspondence and newspaper clippings on various, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- Maarten Keller, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- Gloria Pitzer, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- Lawry's California Center, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- International Chili Society, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- eggs and dairy, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- Los Angeles County Fair, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- chocolate, 1976 - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- Christmas and "Artistry in Dining: the Perfect Meal" exhibit, 1977 December (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - KNX "Meet the Cook" scripts and research -- Joanne Worley, Michelle Evans, Katie Stapleton, Marion Gorman and Jean Nidetch, 1977 -1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" research -- Southern California Restaurant Association press releases and Los Angeles Restaurant Writers Association brochure, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" -- recipes and ideas from listeners, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" -- recipes and ideas from listeners used on show, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Commercial scripts for Bridgford Bread and AFTRA member reports, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - KNX "Food News" and "Meet the Cook" -- Publicity agents of guests, 1977 - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Survey of food and cooking shows-- research and draft for future report "What's Cooking on Television", 1977 October (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "What's Cooking on Television" -- draft of report, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "What's Cooking on Television" -- bound report, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 2 pitches for television food shows, 1977 June and December (Box 4, Folder 4)
      "What's Cooking America?" and "The Great American Cook-Off," a series proposed by Robert Dwan.
    - "Stars in the Morning" -- audition recording script, 18 November 1948 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - CBS brief, 12 May 1950 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - "Taking California Around the World" -- summary report, ca. 1951 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - KNX "Top of the Morning" script, 11 June 1951 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - "You're the Judge" -- scripts, ca. 1976 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      12 scripts (numbers 105 -117)
    - "Meet the Cook" -- script, recipe, and press release, ca. 1978 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - "The Ralph Story show" -- special edition, undated (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Television, Serial Programs, 1959 - 1982
    Scripts and research materials for programs including Ralph Story's Los Angeles (Scripts only, for shows numbered 1 -248 excluding 229 and 244, which are missing from the collection. MOS indicates Man on the Street survey), KABC Story in Hollywood, KABC Ralph Story's AM, ABC AM America, and KNXT/CBS Evening News. Dates taken from creator file labels and appear to be airdates; shooting schedules, assignment sheets and taping dates may vary. This series also includes proposals and pilots for television series, as well as production records, memos and some correspondence.
    - CBS "The Big Party by Revlon" -- script and schedule, 1959 October (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - KNXT/CBS Big News -- Human Predicament segments, 1963 and 1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Scripts for "Planned escape," Tut curse, JFK assassination, death of Robert Ruark
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- history of program and log; includes detailed contents for episodes (segment topics-- taken from annotated scripts) and rerun dates for each episode, 1963 - 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.1 - 5, 1964 January 14 - 1964 February 11 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      No.1 Legend of Los Angeles City Limits signs, castle hotel, Beverly Hills freeway construction, Union station. 1964 January 14. no.2 Los Angeles and city high-rise apartments and offices; trials of the unemployed actor. 1964 January 21. no.3 Los Angeles City Council; the price of the presidential yacht Potomac; death of the New York Times western edition; rock paintings in Los Angeles area. 1964 January 28. no. 4 he Los Angeles River; the ending of the Potomac story (see no.3); Granada Park ski haven. 1964 February 4. no.5 Baldwin Hills reservoir; Highway 99 and Bakersfield; Normandie Village; Margaret Chase Smith; the National Cigar Company. 1964 February 11.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.6 - 10, 1964 February 18 - 1964 March 17 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      No.6 The La Brea Tar Pits; Mexican-American communities; Los Angeles Tattoo Studio; news quips. 1964 February 18. no.7 The Southland Commuter Council; prize-fighting in Los Angeles; what fourteen year olds think about their names; the Star Spangled Banner at Grove theater in Upland (see no.8, 10); the Count Dracula Society. 1964 February 25. no.8 Time capsules; the world of art and pop-art; the West Coast Playboy Club; Venice and artist Billy AL Bengston; the Star Spangled Banner in an Upland movie house (see no. 7, 10). 1964 March 3. no.9 The Metropolitan Transit Authority; pool-hall and other problems in Tarzana; quips on conventions in Los Angeles. 1964 March 10. no.10 Spring in Southern California; the haunted history of Griffith Park and the Feliz Adobe; the Star Spangled Banner in an Upland movie house (see no.7, 8). 1964 March 17.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.11 - 15, 1964 March 24 - 1964 April 21 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      No. 11 Hermits in Los Angeles (see also no.15); social visits then and now; the greeting-card business; corporal punishment in the Los Angeles schools. 1964 March 24. no.12 Reverend James Price Sandefer; surfing wet and dry. 1964 March 31. no.13 President Johnson criticized for speeding; Catalina Island (see also no.14); a model United Nations; two young Southern Californians on their way to South America in a model A. 1964 April 7. no.14 Teenagers reactions to the fold-up of radio station KRLA; Tony Cornero, the Rex and the Lux; horseshoers or smithies; added quips on Catalina (see no.13). 1964 April 14. no.15 Alcohol and animals, especially dogs; Henri Charpentier's; Restaurant La Rue's back-door tradition; Shakespeare; letter from hermit Sparks Freesoul (see no.11). 1964 April 21.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.16 -20, 1964 April 28 - 1964 May 26 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      No.16 Los Angeles aqueduct and the Owens Valley. 1964 April 28. no.17 The Owens Valley citizens' attitudes towards Angelenos; daredevils and stuntmen; the Blonde Age. 1964 May 5. no.18 Ruby Anders - the only female cab driver in Los Angeles; Brittini of North Hollywood, an art factory; The Barber of Seville, a barber shop and art school; Howard Hughes' secret hangar on Terminal Island. 1964 May 12. no.19 Political elephants; parking and parking lots; UCLA; David Geber, a 13 year old cellist and aviator. 1964 May 19. no.20 Fink Street; Winnie Ruth Judd - murderess; soccer. 1964 May 26.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.21 - 25, 1964 June 9 - 1964 July 7 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      No.21 Statewide science fair in the City of Commerce; the health food industry. 1964 June 9. no.22 College seniors and their immediate plans - a survey; the Golden Age of Radio; hills in Los Angeles that are comparable to those in San Francisco. 1964 June 16. no.23 Grunion hunting; the so-called Right of Eminent Domain in Los Angeles; the exhibit at the State Museum of Science and Industry of war booty. 1964 June 23. no.24 Mart Toggweiler's submarine; the swallows and the pigeons of San Juan Capistrano; memorial to Dr. Rufus Bernhard Von Klein- Smid. 1964 June 30. no.25 Henry Gaylord Wilshire and his boulevard; a dog named Theodore. 1964 July 7.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.26 - 30, 1964 July 21 - 1964 September 15 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      No.26 Los Angeles street names; movie star map business; Rustic Canyon; the track and field meet with the U.S.S.R. 1964 July 21. no.27 Sidewalk caf?s in Los Angeles; bank robbery; the Sons of the Revolution and their fight to save their Los Angeles headquarters. 1964 August 4. no.28 The dos and don'ts of handling Old Glory; the nuns at Immaculate Heart College; historical sites in Los Angeles county. 1964 August 18. no.29 Should we change party emblems? - a survey; Californian girls in the Miss America pageant; baseball records; oil derricks, an Los Angeles symbol. 1964 September 1. no.30 Adventures of Tarzan in Los Angeles; Mount Lowe - vacation wonderland 1893-1930s. 1964 September 15.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no. 31 - 35, 1964 September 22 - 1964 October 20 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      No. 31 The coin shortage in Los Angeles; variety of churches and faiths in Los Angeles; public housing project for birds. 1964 September 22. no.32 Norman Thatcher - freeway crawler but hobby speedster; the monster business; British colonials in Los Angeles, missing persons. 1964 September 29. no.33 The moon - symbol of romance; Hubert Eaton and Forest Lawn; gold in Southern California. 1964 October 6.no.34 Pismo Beach and the World's Fair, 1972; freeway fence riders. 1964 October 13. no.35 400 So. Alvarado Street and the death of William Desmond Taylor; the San Antonio winery; the Lesser Towers. 1964 October 20
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.36 - 40, 1964 October 27 - 1964 December 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      No.36 Expressions Angelenos hate most - a survey; Grand Central Air Terminal in Glendale; planned playgrounds; propositions on the November 3, 1964 ballot. 1964 October 27. no.37 Public Library pilfering; the auto eater or the recycling of automobiles; Mr. Morris Robert - Cerritos Channel bridge superintendant; T.V. Medicitis. 1964 November 10. no.38 The Hundred Years' War of Pershing Square; Jackson Barnett and his wife Anna - Indian claims to California; the natural pond on University High School's campus. 1964 November 17. no.39 What's middle age? - a survey; Los Angeles charter chapter of the American Society of Theater Organ Enthusiasts; Ellsworth (Sonny) Wisecarver. 1964 November 24. no.40 Quest for a national flower; the fake flower business and the fresh flower business; where have all the orange groves gone?; therapeutic wife beating.1964 December 1.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.41 - 45, 1964 December 8 - 1965 January 5 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      No.41 The Hollywoodland sign; the privately built dormitory complexes; the Bank Caf? of San Pedro; the Green Forest Celery Heart plant. 1964 December 8. no.42 Comments on the professional techniques of T.V.'s high school teacher Mr. Novak; the oil industry; Palm Springs. 1964 December 15. no.43 Santa Claus; the town of Boron; Juan Gomez's tamales. 1964 December 22. no.44 The Art and Science of Barbering; men's grooming salons; the Los Angeles County Museum of Art's move from Exposition Park to Hancock Park. 1964 December 29. no.45 Fancy food; famous planes and their pilots - Joan Merriam Smith and Douglas Wrong Way Corrigan; Captain Max Schumacher the freeway watcher. 1965 January 5.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.46 - 50, 1965 January 12 - 1965 February 9 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      No.46 Aim?e Semple McPherson, Evangelist; Pershing Square (see no.38) and Boston Park. 1965 January 12. no.47 College study sickness - a survey; Los Angeles air traffic jams; the wrecking business and building demolition in Los Angeles; quips on the show (i.e. Ralph Story's Los Angeles). 1965 January 19. no.48 Manchester Boddy and the Daily News. 1965 January 26. no.49 The witchcraft renaissance; the Los Angeles Music Center; registration of candidates for office in Los Angeles city elections. 1965 February 2. no.50 Discrimination in golfing; Commander Bonner - the city dog catcher; Valentine's Day; hate mail, hate literature, and the Anti-Defamation League. 1965 February 9.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.51 - 55, 1965 February 16 - 1965 March 16 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      No.51 How can we glamorize Hollywood Boulevard? - a survey; Walburga Oesterreich and Otto Sanhuber; the coin shortage and the Bank of Los Angeles. 1965 February 16. no.52 Japanese "raid" on L.A. 1942 - Los Angeles prepares for possible air-raid; Burbank; insurance companies. 1965 February 23. no.53 California Division of Highways and Foster Park; the California condor. 1965 March 2. no.54 Definition of the color blue - a survey; Serra Retreat; Los Angeles repossession firms. 1965 March 9. no.55 More on the Battle of Los Angeles (see no.52); Lysistrata as played in 1932; the Southern California blimp. 1965 March 16.
    - KNXT Ralph Story's Los Angeles -- no.56 - 60, 1965 March 23 - 1965 April 20 (Box 6, Folder 4)